# Shubhangi Agarwal

shubhangiat.github.io | in shubhangi-agarwal

■ shubhangi.agarwal8@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I am a researcher with a background in **Graph Mining** and **Machine Learning**. I have developed various algorithms based on statistical analysis for **Subgraph Querying** in large complex graphs. Some of the many areas that can benefit from the querying of subgraph structures are **information extraction**, **recommendation systems**, **disease diagnostics**, **fraud detection** are. I am intersted in developing effective and efficient algorithms for analyzing complex data structures using state-of-the-art machine learning techniques.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh, India

2014 - current

CGPA: 8.25

**Bachelor of Technology Computer Engineering** 

Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat, Gujarat, India

CGPA: 8.71 2010 - 2014

Supervisor: Arnab Bhattacharva

#### **PHD THESIS**

#### **Subgraph Matching and Mining in Large Graphs**

• Developed algorithms for Approximate Subgraph Matching in both deterministic and probabilistic graphs.

• Proposed a Graph Neural Network model for robust node embeddings with positional information.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- "VeNoM: Approximate Subgraph Matching with Enhanced Neighbourhood Structural Information", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, 7th Joint International Conference on Data Science and Management of Data (CODS-COMAD), 2024, India.
- "VerSaChI: Finding Statistically Significant Subgraph Matches using Chebyshev's Inequality", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2021, pages 2812-2816, Australia.
- "GraphReach: Position-Aware Graph Neural Network using Reachability Estimations", Sunil Nishad, **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Arnab Bhattacharya and Sayan Ranu, Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021, pages 1527-1533, Canada.
- "ChiSeL: Graph Similarity Search using Chi-Squared Statistics in Large Probabilistic Graphs", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), 2020, pages 1654-1668, Japan.

### **EXPERIENCES**

External Reviewer 2020 - current

• WSDM (2024), CIKM (2021, 2022), DASFAA (2022), CoDS-COMAD (2020, 2021), KDD (2021)

# **Teaching Assistant (IIT Kanpur)**

Aug 2014 - Apr 2021

• Graded and evaluated projects for various courses of Computer Science.

## **Senior Tutor (IIT Kanpur)**

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018, Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

ullet Led teams of strength  $\sim\!$ 60; Assisted in backend management, paper-setting and grading.

#### **Teaching Assistant for MOOC (NPTEL - Remote)**

July 2017 - Sep 2017

• Crafted objective questions and resolved student queries on Fundamentals of Database Systems.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : C, C++, Java, Python, R, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, Shell scripting

Libraries : PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas

**Tools** : git, LaTeX, Docker, Weka